# **Rovshen Paltayev**

### Software Developer & Engineer

Experienced Software Developer & Engineer with strong data structure, algorithm, problem solving skills.

Background in business and experience in start-up like environment with ability to achieve goals on a strict deadline. Highly motivated cross-functional team member.



2017-01

### **Experience**

#### **Software Developer - CS Assistant** 2016-08 -

### **North American University**

- Engineered and Developed script testing framework for reporting and grading purposes with Java, TestNG, and Extent Reports.
- Developed various front-end animations on web pages using JavaScript.
- Decreased CPU consumption of animations by more than 30% compared to other conventional implementations.

### **Software Engineer** 2017-01 present

### **Brighten Technologies LLC**

- Start-up like environment with various types of responsibilities mainly residing around development and support in an agile development environment.
- Developed automation scripts to efficiently source target products using Python and increased product sourcing capabilities by at least 5 times..
- Continuously increased performance and speed of the application and ability to overcome certain limitations of scraping scripts by integrating Selenium.
- Provided continuous IT support to existing clients in various technical/non-technical related topics maintaining high satisfaction rate.
- Participated in sales presentations due to ability to translate user needs into easy-to-understand software solutions.

# **Education**

# present

### North American University - MS Computer Science

Masters in Science of Computer Science Software Engineering - Expecting to graduate in May 2019



## **Personal Projects**

#### **Face Recognition Webapp** 2018-07 -2018-11

- Developed face recognition web application using React.js with HTML/CSS and Javascript
- Developed back-end api using PostgreSQL, Node.js and Express.js
- Increased security for users by using Bcrypt library for storing user sensitive data
- React is one of my recent obsessions, this one is a result of it. Refer to my portfolio for more details on the project

### 2018-03 -

### 2018-04

- **Robo Friends**
- Initial React webapp for testing purposes and was developed for fun
- Implemented search feature with component state change to render in every input



### **Personal Info**

#### **Address**

Houston TX

### **Phone**

(832) 630 8632

#### E-mail

rowshenpaltayev@gmail.com

#### **WWW**

www.rovshen.com

#### **GitHub**

https://github.com/rpaltayev



## **Programming** Languages

Java

**Python** 

HTML/CSS

**Javascript** 

SQL/PostgreSQL



### **Other**

Git & Github

**React & Redux** 

Node.js & Express.js

Java/Python Selenium

JUnit/TestNG

**POM Design** 

Cucumber

**Jenkins** 

Maven



### Languages

**Turkish** 

Russian

Refer to my portfolio for more details on the project

#### **Travel Guide** 2018-10 -

2018-12 Open Source Project run by community of developers.

• Assisted in various optimization changes to the project source code.



## Awards and Certifications

OCA Certified Associate - Java SE Programmer 2017-11

2010-04 1st Place in Programming Project Competition - Turkmenistan